<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An answer to Mr. Lenthall's pretended case</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1700</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B01391</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A3369</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R170321</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">52211886</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 52211886</idno>
            <idno type="VID">175403</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B01391)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 175403)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2732:21)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An answer to Mr. Lenthall's pretended case</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[S.l. :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1700?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Suggested date of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Page [2] has half-title: To Mr. Lenthall's case.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Lincoln's Inn Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Lenthall, William, --  Mr. --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term>Cutler, John, --  Sir.</term>
               <term>Possessory interests in land --  England --  Cases --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="answer">
            <pb facs="tcp:175403:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>An ANSWER To Mr. <hi>Lenthall</hi>'s Pretended CASE.</head>
            <p n="1">I. THAT inſtead of 12000 <abbr>
                  <hi>l.</hi>
               </abbr> due from Mr. <hi>Lenthall</hi> at Sir <hi>John Cutler</hi>'s Death, (as the Caſe ſuggeſts) there was above 14500 <abbr>
                  <hi>l.</hi>
               </abbr> then due, as has ſince been own'd, under Mr. <hi>Lenthall</hi>'s Hand and Seal.</p>
            <p n="2">II. That the Accompt ſtated in <hi>May</hi> 1697, is the Third paſs'd by Mr. <hi>Lenthall</hi> under Hand and Seal, ſince Sir <hi>John Cutler</hi>'s Death; and all of them were paſs'd deliberately and fairly, as has appear'd by the Originals produc'd to the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee, where the ſame (with what is ſince incurred) have been Examined in Mr. <hi>Lenthall</hi>'s preſence, and he could make no Objection, becauſe of Vouchers to eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Article that required them, and he could not pretend Surprize, as owning to have had Coppys of Accompts deliver'd to him.</p>
            <p n="3">III. That the Pretence about Mr. <hi>Boulter</hi>'s making an Abatement, is altogether frivolous, many Perſons can witneſs upon occaſion: And as to Mr. <hi>Folkes</hi>'s being to have 1000 <abbr>
                  <hi>l.</hi>
               </abbr> on that account, 'tis already diſprov'd upon Oath.</p>
            <p n="4">IV. That the Deeds executed by Mr. <hi>Lenthall,</hi> about the Eſtate and Office, were done voluntarily and deliberately, has fully appear'd to a Committee of Parliament two years ago; where the ſaid Deeds (with Mr. <hi>Card,</hi> and others con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern'd therein) were examin'd in Mr. <hi>Lenthall</hi>'s preſence, and he declar'd the Deeds to be with his Approbation, and that he directed them to be drawn.</p>
            <p n="5">V. That tho' Mr. <hi>Lenthall</hi> ſays he only knew ſince <hi>May</hi> laſt, that the Mort<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gages were Aſſign'd to the Earl of <hi>Radnor,</hi> yet there's very ample Proof that he was acquainted with the Transferr as ſoon as 'twas agreed upon, and he declar'd his Satisfaction with it: Beſides, for two years laſt paſt, he has receiv'd, from time to time of the Earl of <hi>Radnor,</hi> ſeveral large Summs of Money, and under his Hand and Seal has charg'd and annex'd the ſame to the Securities ſo Aſſign'd as aforeſaid; for the proof whereof, and of this fair and regular paſſing the Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compts and Deeds, the Committees and the Journals are referr'd to.</p>
            <p>That there was any certain Rent to be paid for the Marſhal's Office, is deny'd, the preſent Marſhal holding it on Tryal; and by his Accompt it does appear, that nothing has been made on't, nor indeed is like to be, while the Warden of the <hi>Fleet</hi> makes ſo bold with Acts of Parliament, and bids Defiance to the Laws.</p>
            <p>As to Mr. <hi>Lenthall</hi>'s value of the <hi>Oxfordſhire</hi> Eſtate, and the Priſon, 'tis only anſwer'd, That the Earl of <hi>Radnor</hi> is willing that the ſame be Sold to the beſt advantage, for his Lordſhip deſires but what is juſtly due to him, and he wiſhes the Eſtate and Priſon would amount to it; however it is hoped that Mr. <hi>Lenthall</hi>'s trifling and falſe Suggeſtions will not prejudice or leſſen his Lordſhips Right, nor hinder ſo great an Advantage to the Publick, as the Bill to pay the Incumbrance, and diſſolve the Priſon would effect.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:175403:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
         </div>
         <div type="docket_title">
            <p>To Mr. <hi>Lenthall's</hi> Caſe.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
